<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>佩佩的小窝 - others</title><link href="https://yx-peipei.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yx-peipei.github.io/feeds/others.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yx-peipei.github.io/</id><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Keep fit during Corona lockdown</title><link href="https://yx-peipei.github.io/others/Keep%20fit%20during%20Corona%20%20lockdown.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>peipei</name></author><id>tag:yx-peipei.github.io,2020-05-01:/others/Keep fit during Corona  lockdown.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I originally built up this blog, I was intended to record my life; however, when I revise this blog after three years, I find it turns out to be a personal diary, sharing what I read and what is flowing inside my mind. A bit metaphysical, too much spiritual …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I originally built up this blog, I was intended to record my life; however, when I revise this blog after three years, I find it turns out to be a personal diary, sharing what I read and what is flowing inside my mind. A bit metaphysical, too much spiritual puzzles. However, I am not that sentimentalism as you might imagine, neither the same as a philosophy fellow who only cares about the conceptual world; in everyday life, I spend almost two hours a day to keep fit, by sport and by healthy eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy diet is no doubt the most important part for keeping fit, I am a great advocate for a natural diet. I am not interested in any fancy diet plan such as low-carb or low-fat or keto, I believe most of those research articles are not rigorous enough ; instead, I am more focused on the natural flavour of food: less salty dish with as less processed ingredients as possible. Perhaps I am too prickly on what I choose to eat, my daily calorie intake is usually in deficit, but I would like to say: eat natural, eat simple and do not pay too much attention to the diet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the workouts, I have more tips to share.  I have been the member of a luxury gym (Third Space) for more than three years. The membership fee is very pricy, almost all my friends cancelled their memberships due to the cost, but I keep it until now,  partly because I go to gym almost everyday, which makes each single entrance seemed  less expensive, partly because the classes are really  'haute de gamme'. Incidentally, one of my main  principles regarding to the consumption is,  if I really need something, I would go for the best thus usually most expensive choice. Coming back to the classes in this gym: I often attend the lunchtime classes of HIIT style, submerging myself in the following choices: Extreme, SweatX, Metaburn and Spinning. Each class is a 45-min workout including warm-up and stretches, guided by the coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Extreme' has four rounds of eight minutes HIIT workout, each eight-minute has four 30-second exercises four times: exercise I and III are more like body-weight strength,  typical examples are lungis, plank with shoulder tap, step push-ups;  whilst exercise II and IV are mainly designed to boost the heart rates: jumping-lungis, step tap traverse, burpees and frog-jumps.  Instrument-wise, a step is the only requirement. My takeaway from this class is: &lt;strong&gt;If people jump all the time, it won't make them very sweaty, if people keep doing strength, they won't feel hot neither.  A combination of jumping and strength can make people feel tired and sweaty quite soon&lt;/strong&gt;, and those classes will gain a  reputation for 'effective fat burning'. People believe the sweat is the tear of fat. Really fat-burning? Who knows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'SweatX' is another calorie-killer in Third Space. This class is equipped with a more fancy stuff: a headset, because we need onlive instructions from the trainer when sprinting on the treadmill. In addition, the coach will prepare us with a set of heavy weights, usually two 6s/8s/10s kg. The training is composed with 2 rounds of running and 2 rounds of floor weight trainning, each of them lasts 8 minutes. First round of running goes for high gradient: it usually begins with 8/10/12 km/h with 2% grade, then top up gradually to 8/10% with the same speed; once peaked, we will release the tensions on the leg  by a gradual decrease of 2% every minute,  but an increase of 2km/h in the speed for compensation. It is not that hard as it looked like, because we usually have a 30-sec rest in the middle of this round. Second round of running is mainly for a faster speed. Keeping the grade as 0.5% but the coach gradually asks us to run into 15/16 kph. Of course for those harder-core friends, they can reach up to 20kph and keep it for one minute. Sometimes the coach would ask us to set a distance target, say run for 160 meters with the maximum speed in 40s, then rest for 20s, then repeat them for 5 times. That 20s' rest is a must, which means the 40s' work requires us a speed as if we are catching the train.  Floor round is for dumbbell strength training. Sally, one of the main coach, likes to design this section with bundles of snatch with dumbbells, deadlift, shoulder press, push-up with windmill or with dumbbell row, lunges, arm rows, burpees, butterfly sit up, etc. Usually we have four to six exercises each round; for the first turn, each exercise requires 12 repetition; second turn, 9 reps; third turn, 6 then finish with 3 reps. Once finished, we are allowed to take a small rest until the next running session. After 45 minutes, we are all liked to be soaked in the water. In a word, the way SweatX makes us sweat, is again as what I described above: &lt;strong&gt;a mixture of cardio and strength&lt;/strong&gt;. During the strength exercises, once  the heart rate begins to decline, we add some half-burpees; during the running, once the body is accustomed to one speed, we would hear a 'lovely' lady voice from the headset: increase your speed/gradient by 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a sport expert, neither did I spend a lot of time in optimizing my workout routine, but this method does work for me.  My fitter body is the evidence. In the past few years,  I see so many girls around me get belly fat that easily after leaving school and beginning 9-5 style job; I see how easily people become lazy and become accustomed in the daily routine. More fearful, they do not realize their laziness. For the workout, and even for the life, we need prompt changes, we need  to design them for an irregular routine. Memory in the mind may be good, it will protect us from making the same mistake and save time (as machine learning principles); memory in the body is not that good in most cases, it will minimize our energy consumption, make us lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of lockdown, I usually did the 6km morning run every two days; but now, only twice a week. Of course there are excuses such as  the train schedule is reduced so much that I cannot easily return home after running to West Hampstead; but a deeper reason is I find it more convenient to follow the so-called youtube workout , satisfy myself that I have done that daily exercises, I tick the To-Do box . To be honest, even though I keep doing a lot high-intensity workout from Devil Pamela or Keep, it still fails to  achieve the same benefits of running outdoor for 40 minutes. Fresh air, the first sunshine in the morning, the up-and-downs on the road, the very attention on breathing, those things will reset my mind, release my tension, throw those tiny troubles away from my body. I think, it is  the true purpose of keep moving. Keeping fit is not just keeping the body fit, neither  keeping the  number on the weight balance nioce, it is also keeping the mind fit and positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hendon Park" class="img-responsive" src="/images/HendonParkLateSpring2020.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last challenge for you: it is a popular HIIT from China Hupu that I find worthy trying. For the english translation it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A-Z Muscle challenge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: 30x jumping-jacks  B: 20x crunches C: 30x squats D:15x push-ups
E: 1 min wall squat F: 10x burpees G: 1min Plank
H: 20x squats I: 50x jumping-jack J: 15x crunches K: 10x push-ups 
L: 15x mountain-climbers M: 20x burpees N: 25x burpees
O: 40x jumping-jacks P:20x mountain-climbers Q: 30x crunches
R: 15x push-ups S: 30x burpees T:15x squats
U: 1-min plank V: 2min wall squat W: 20x burpees
X: 60x jumping-jacks Y: 10x cruches Z: 20x push-ups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can finish it in 27min, how about you? 
&lt;img alt="肌本挑战" class="img-responsive" src="/images/肌本挑战.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="others"></category><category term="Lifestyle"></category></entry><entry><title>关于学习的一些感悟</title><link href="https://yx-peipei.github.io/others/%E5%85%B3%E4%BA%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E6%84%9F%E6%82%9F.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>peipei</name></author><id>tag:yx-peipei.github.io,2020-03-22:/others/关于学习的一些感悟.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;前几天跟学姐夫catch up的时候碰巧谈到了利用工作之余学习的事情。学姐夫是个视野比较开阔的人，对新鲜事物一直保有敏感心态，但有了宝宝之后，哪怕有双方父母帮忙照顾小孩，时间也不大能够自主掌握，他说，现在已经基本不可能进行系统化学习了。当谈及我最近利用地铁时间听吴晓波的《精讲五十本商业经典》时，他说，这叫做碎片化学习，也是他平时能做到的了。这不是我第一次听到系统化学习和碎片化学习这两个概念了，但却是第一次让我开始反思自己的学习方式。对于一般人来说，能坚持听一些有知识性的比如说吴晓波的财经就已经算是迈向上进学生的一步了，然而这只是学习的一种方式，并非总是很高效，有些类似黑瞎子捡玉米，捡一个掉一个的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其实说起来，毕业以后，我的学习读书状态一直都是碎片化的，这源于我对广泛领域的好奇。我觉得定期做个读书总结是个很好的习惯，哪怕很多书都是翻了几页就扔下了，哪怕只是写下书籍的名字，也是对自己的所花时间和精力的交代，更重要的是，这些书是对自己的再认识。从你看过的书或者手机里经常查阅的阅读材料，便知你当下是什么状态。在最近一年里，我读过的最多的是地缘政治、历史、科幻、经管和意识流文学。而在之前两三年，基本都是阅读哲学书籍，探究一下生命的意义什么的。但总体来说都是些人文社科书籍，这也映照出我的真正爱好在于此。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了一些知识的积累，这几年对很多事情也多了一些包容。拿碎片化学习来说，以前有一种偏见，认为那是时间管理做得不够好的人才采取的学习方式 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;前几天跟学姐夫catch up的时候碰巧谈到了利用工作之余学习的事情。学姐夫是个视野比较开阔的人，对新鲜事物一直保有敏感心态，但有了宝宝之后，哪怕有双方父母帮忙照顾小孩，时间也不大能够自主掌握，他说，现在已经基本不可能进行系统化学习了。当谈及我最近利用地铁时间听吴晓波的《精讲五十本商业经典》时，他说，这叫做碎片化学习，也是他平时能做到的了。这不是我第一次听到系统化学习和碎片化学习这两个概念了，但却是第一次让我开始反思自己的学习方式。对于一般人来说，能坚持听一些有知识性的比如说吴晓波的财经就已经算是迈向上进学生的一步了，然而这只是学习的一种方式，并非总是很高效，有些类似黑瞎子捡玉米，捡一个掉一个的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其实说起来，毕业以后，我的学习读书状态一直都是碎片化的，这源于我对广泛领域的好奇。我觉得定期做个读书总结是个很好的习惯，哪怕很多书都是翻了几页就扔下了，哪怕只是写下书籍的名字，也是对自己的所花时间和精力的交代，更重要的是，这些书是对自己的再认识。从你看过的书或者手机里经常查阅的阅读材料，便知你当下是什么状态。在最近一年里，我读过的最多的是地缘政治、历史、科幻、经管和意识流文学。而在之前两三年，基本都是阅读哲学书籍，探究一下生命的意义什么的。但总体来说都是些人文社科书籍，这也映照出我的真正爱好在于此。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了一些知识的积累，这几年对很多事情也多了一些包容。拿碎片化学习来说，以前有一种偏见，认为那是时间管理做得不够好的人才采取的学习方式；若是上进且专注的人，肯定有能力挤出时间进行系统专业学习，而增加一技之长。现在想来，碎片化学习和系统化学习同等重要，系统化学习可以免自己陷入什么都懂一些但也回答不了什么问题的肤浅；碎片化学习能够开拓视野，保持一个open和好奇的人生状态；系统化学习能通过不断重复的方式对概念加以巩固，碎片化学习只是些浮光掠影、惊鸿一瞥。书籍也不再是知识承载的唯一媒介，视频音频都可以解构知识。但文字应该是学习的主要方式，毕竟视频音频给大脑皮层带来的刺激是直接即时的，而学习的过程是一个需要反思的过程，它需要时间的延后性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以前跟妈妈科普过三年长一技的学习方式，意如其名，每三年花所有的剩余精力去学习一项新事物，可以是厨艺、可以是品酒、也可以是摄影。工作毕业到现在也有三年，但也没有仅去专注学习某一项。诚然，专注力不足是我的性格缺陷；但即便自己有那个专注力，也并非在一开始就知道喜欢什么东西并可以为此有一个长期的commitment。反倒喜欢在知识的花园里走走停停，看到远处的一簇玫瑰过去瞅瞅，突然发现了旁边又一束不知名的小花也很漂亮。常感叹知识的海洋无限，只恨自己只有一个人生的时间去发掘。时光便在感恨和“拈花惹草”中匆匆流逝，随着视野愈发开阔，感恨也愈发频繁，专注的时间愈发稀少。从今往后的学习，还是要注意分清主次的呀！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;突然想到之前读过的一本小书：《刻意练习：从新手到大师》。这本书除了提出每个新技能培养需要花一万个小时去建立之外，还提出学习要像学围棋的人一样，通过大量练习在脑子里形成类似条件反射区；围棋大师并非都天生聪明绝顶，他们中大部分人只是在长期的时间积累中，对各种棋盘与相应策略了如指掌，哪怕看到新的棋盘，他们也能建立起与旧棋盘的连接。其实阿尔法狗能够在围棋中大败李世石，也是因为棋类运动是需要前期数据库的建立，在记忆力方面，机器的数据储存能力比人类的选择性记忆可是精确完整得多。形成条件反射区一是需要大量积累，二是需要一个反馈过程，在学习方面的具体操作就是复习、练习与总结。但学习的乐趣并不在于单纯记忆的存储，它在于旧知识向外拓展延伸的生长力，在于融会贯通那一刹那的欣喜；正如人一样，学习也是一个有生命的机体。&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="others"></category><category term="Lifestyle"></category></entry><entry><title>女人养生暖当先</title><link href="https://yx-peipei.github.io/others/%E5%A5%B3%E4%BA%BA%E5%85%BB%E7%94%9F%E6%9A%96%E5%BD%93%E5%85%88.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>peipei</name></author><id>tag:yx-peipei.github.io,2016-12-11:/others/女人养生暖当先.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天一口气看了两集CCTV10的《健康之路》栏目，主题是“女人养生暖当先”，认为有必要整理一下中医大漂亮吴老师传授的知识。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;女人主阴，再加上生养孩子都需要女人大量精血付出，所以一般的女生都或多或少会出现阳气不足的症状。倒不一定大家都是阳虚体质，但是普遍的冬天手脚冰凉，背上老感觉凉飕飕的，月经不调乃至很难怀孕，这都是“寒”的症状。有时候，腹部肥胖都是因为体寒。那么，女同胞们需要从哪些方面去调理呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;漂亮吴阿姨给了五个小宝箱：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;适量运动&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先吴阿姨让大家现场跳广场舞，运动至微微发汗。关于运动，真是各路人马说法不一。最近超级火爆的健身app keep鼓励大家每日举铁，大汗淋漓的女汉子们纷纷晒腹肌晒马甲线，自我感觉良好。但是吴阿姨说了，运动能生阳，但出大量的汗却能带走阳气，所以运动至微微发汗是最佳的。那么可能对于减脂增肌的人来说，要不断加大运动量突破平台期；但是对体寒的人来讲，运动要适可而止。唉，这个度真难把握。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;泡水良方&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大家运动了会儿也渴了，这时候吴阿姨请大家喝了一杯水。这杯水是由锁阳15g，龙眼干15g和桑葚9g加开水泡成，可以泡上一天。锁阳和龙眼干都是温性的，桑葚略阴性。《黄帝内经·素问 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天一口气看了两集CCTV10的《健康之路》栏目，主题是“女人养生暖当先”，认为有必要整理一下中医大漂亮吴老师传授的知识。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;女人主阴，再加上生养孩子都需要女人大量精血付出，所以一般的女生都或多或少会出现阳气不足的症状。倒不一定大家都是阳虚体质，但是普遍的冬天手脚冰凉，背上老感觉凉飕飕的，月经不调乃至很难怀孕，这都是“寒”的症状。有时候，腹部肥胖都是因为体寒。那么，女同胞们需要从哪些方面去调理呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;漂亮吴阿姨给了五个小宝箱：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;适量运动&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先吴阿姨让大家现场跳广场舞，运动至微微发汗。关于运动，真是各路人马说法不一。最近超级火爆的健身app keep鼓励大家每日举铁，大汗淋漓的女汉子们纷纷晒腹肌晒马甲线，自我感觉良好。但是吴阿姨说了，运动能生阳，但出大量的汗却能带走阳气，所以运动至微微发汗是最佳的。那么可能对于减脂增肌的人来说，要不断加大运动量突破平台期；但是对体寒的人来讲，运动要适可而止。唉，这个度真难把握。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;泡水良方&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大家运动了会儿也渴了，这时候吴阿姨请大家喝了一杯水。这杯水是由锁阳15g，龙眼干15g和桑葚9g加开水泡成，可以泡上一天。锁阳和龙眼干都是温性的，桑葚略阴性。《黄帝内经·素问》上讲，“善补阳者，必阴中求阳”，就是讲补阳的方子要加少许补阴的药物，这样阳气便能更好地融入阴性体质中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“美丽冻人”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最近国内的审美观偏向欧美化，而欧美穿搭在冬季的一项法则就是“上身保暖，下身有型”，于是乎菇凉们冬天哪怕穿牛仔裤，也是破了洞的。本人虽然没那么夸张，但冬天裤子也是不够保暖，整条腿经常跟冰棍一样。吴阿姨介绍一种方法，可以用来敷腿：用几块砭石，热水暖热后分别敷在左右腿的委中穴、血海穴和梁丘穴各十五分钟。这样可以暖通经络，还能瘦腿哪！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;胃寒也很恼人&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;小时候的我，也是越到冬天越喜欢吃冰淇淋，每年元宵节晚上看灯火时都举着个蛋筒，可惬意了。但现在，真不大敢吃凉的了，一吃多就胃堵；素食惯了，也消化不动肉肉了；治痘的时候，也是吃各种排毒的药，那可都是泻火的寒药呀。所以这个胃，也有点儿寒。吴阿姨给的妙招是：醋泡姜。姜大家都知道，是热性的；醋呢，可以收敛阳气。关于做法呢，大家先切片，再加少许盐，盐杀七八个小时后把浸出的水倒掉；然后加老陈醋（注意一定是粮食酿的醋）放入密闭容器，在阴暗处放一周就可以吃了，一个月内吃完。有人会问，这个姜皮要不要扔？姜皮是寒性的，如果胃寒很严重，还是把姜皮给扔掉吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;宫暖气色就好&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;宫寒这个话题吴阿姨讲了整整一集，看来这个问题的重要性不言而喻。宫寒是一系列问题的合称，比较典型的是，有三成的不孕不育来自于宫寒体质，平时女孩子的月经不调、痛经、月经量少也与此相关。﻿哪怕是怀了孕，也有很大几率出现胎停育，导致胎死腹中。宝宝有点怕怕的呢。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那么有什么养生方法么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;第一是脐疗：大家可以做个小香包，放上丁香20g、小茴香20g和细辛10g，拿着一条长布包在肚脐上一晚上，月经前一周和月经期使用。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;第二去药店买妇女痛经丸&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;第三是喝橘普水。橘普是（干湿）橘皮加普洱做成，然后再加上5g佛手，驱寒效果更好。普洱消脂，橘皮促消化，这方子还能减腹部赘肉呢！
﻿&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果宫寒实在厉害，又想要孩子，可以试试艾附暖宫丸 ，这蜜丸里面有艾叶还有四物（当归、川穹、白芍、地黄）成分。但怀孕后就不要吃了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;最后&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后啰嗦几句昨天看的《文明之旅》中讲的《易经》与医。这期主要介绍了十二消息卦表示人的这一生，分为两个大阶段：从婴幼儿至青壮年，是阳气逐渐上升到全阳乾卦的阶段；从中年到老年，是阴气逐渐上升至全阴坤卦的阶段。在第二阶段中，护持好阳气便显得至关重要，怎么护持呢？除了吃黑色食物补肾，还不要熬夜，避免消极情绪。我认为，对于女孩子，从青年时期就得开始注意保护阳气，尤其是我这种不产热的物种。&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="others"></category><category term="Lifestyle"></category></entry><entry><title>佩佩的小窝铺好啦</title><link href="https://yx-peipei.github.io/others/%E4%BD%A9%E4%BD%A9%E7%9A%84%E5%B0%8F%E7%AA%9D%E9%93%BA%E5%A5%BD%E5%95%A6.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-16T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>peipei</name></author><id>tag:yx-peipei.github.io,2016-11-16:/others/佩佩的小窝铺好啦.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;我是一个学数理的小文青。我喜欢看纸质书，写钢笔字，做读书笔记，摘抄好句子。小时候语文成绩还不错（我怀疑是老师改卷子时故意放水以讨好我妈），每回被奖励一摞一摞的笔记本，封面有小狗小猫，还有小燕子赵薇。如今收拾家里，还能在旮旯角落里拖出来一本一本脏兮兮的好句子摘抄本哪。在巴黎的时候，最喜欢逛玛黑区的moleskin的文具店，不在里面摸索半天我是不会出去的；别的妹子长草的是瓶瓶罐罐，我长草的是Smythson的小牛皮笔记本，无奈囊中羞涩，只好默默画饼充饥。后来搬家搬得多了，书本渐渐也搬不动了，我就开始看kindle电子书，写evernote笔记。每次想跟亲朋好友分享思路时，我只会把笔记转成pdf发给大家。经营一个博客的念头是最近才有的，也没什么动机，可能就是为了当个会开挖掘机的技术文青吧！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我选择用github来写博客，就是为了与（zhuang）时(gao)俱(da)进(shang)。老祖宗告诉我们，这样子是要有代价的，所以我鼓捣了好几天，才把我的小窝给搭建好了。主题之类的细节慢慢再说，重要的是脑子里的东西。如果有人想知道如何搭建自己的博客，请参考两位大婶的博文&lt;a href="https://github.com/X-Wei/x-wei.github.com/blob/master/pelican_dir/content/soft/pelican_github_blog.md"&gt;x-wei&lt;/a&gt;
和&lt;a href="https://farseerfc.me/tag/pelican.html"&gt;farseerfc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个博客的构架呢，我打算从读书笔记 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;我是一个学数理的小文青。我喜欢看纸质书，写钢笔字，做读书笔记，摘抄好句子。小时候语文成绩还不错（我怀疑是老师改卷子时故意放水以讨好我妈），每回被奖励一摞一摞的笔记本，封面有小狗小猫，还有小燕子赵薇。如今收拾家里，还能在旮旯角落里拖出来一本一本脏兮兮的好句子摘抄本哪。在巴黎的时候，最喜欢逛玛黑区的moleskin的文具店，不在里面摸索半天我是不会出去的；别的妹子长草的是瓶瓶罐罐，我长草的是Smythson的小牛皮笔记本，无奈囊中羞涩，只好默默画饼充饥。后来搬家搬得多了，书本渐渐也搬不动了，我就开始看kindle电子书，写evernote笔记。每次想跟亲朋好友分享思路时，我只会把笔记转成pdf发给大家。经营一个博客的念头是最近才有的，也没什么动机，可能就是为了当个会开挖掘机的技术文青吧！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我选择用github来写博客，就是为了与（zhuang）时(gao)俱(da)进(shang)。老祖宗告诉我们，这样子是要有代价的，所以我鼓捣了好几天，才把我的小窝给搭建好了。主题之类的细节慢慢再说，重要的是脑子里的东西。如果有人想知道如何搭建自己的博客，请参考两位大婶的博文&lt;a href="https://github.com/X-Wei/x-wei.github.com/blob/master/pelican_dir/content/soft/pelican_github_blog.md"&gt;x-wei&lt;/a&gt;
和&lt;a href="https://farseerfc.me/tag/pelican.html"&gt;farseerfc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个博客的构架呢，我打算从读书笔记，数据学习笔记，时事评析以及时尚分析进行。嗯，先这样吧。&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="others"></category><category term="others"></category></entry></feed>